# **Ricky Davis**

## **Building Engineer - School District of Philadelphia**

Philadelphia, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Ricky-Davis/a726285cbb43033d

Highly dedicated, motivated and energetic facilities professional with years of experience, with a commitment to excellence and an outstanding track record of success in overseeing in all aspects of HVAC facilities. With outstanding interpersonal communication skill, and the ability to coordinate work outcomes with directors, engineers, facility managers, state and local building inspectors, as well as contractors and subcontractors. The knowledge of and hands on experience with building systems, including HVAC equipment, kitchen equipment, electrical distribution systems, fire suppression systems, plumbing systems and refrigeration systems.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Building Engineer**

School District of Philadelphia - Philadelphia, PA - 2009 to Present

Worked hands on with building systems including HVAC systems, Water, Fire and Atmospheric Boilers, Steam Distribution systems, Heat Exchangers, repairs/service oil guns, PM Pumps and Air Handlers.

•Absorption Centrifugal and Reciprocating Chillers, Roof Top Packaged Air

Conditioners, Exhaust Fans and all are relating auxiliary equipment.

- •Inspecting maintenance equipment and general repair work of trades mechanics and service technicians to assure quality service and safety for the facility.
- •Fire Suppression, Electrical, Plumbing and Water Treatment systems.
- •Provided utilities such as: light, heat and power.
- •Installation and inspection of the boiler room, facility systems and equipment
- •Troubleshoot equipment problems
- •Complete routine preventive maintenance
- •Maintain operator logs, forms and records in accordance with company policy, city and State regulations
- •Class "A" license (Engineer)

#### **Bus Chauffeur**

School District of Philadelphia - Philadelphia, PA - 2004 to 2009

Monitored the safety and well being of students while transporting them to and from designated locations.

- •Administered first aid as needed
- Maintain operator log, forms and accident reports
- •Worked cohesively with dispatcher, depot manager and mechanic told ensure daily task completed
- •Established relationships with families and caregivers of students transported

### **EDUCATION**

## **Diploma in Diesel Technology**

Ohio Diesel Technical College - Cleveland, OH 1998 to 1999